<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cicd on My learning and diary</title>
    <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/cicd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cicd on My learning and diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 20:10:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/cicd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CICD</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/06/cicd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 20:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/06/cicd/</guid>
      <description>I shared one of CICD I designed and implemented in linkedin. It is good to keep here as well. I researched several options and put my thought at Reflection on implementation of CICD using argo-workflows
   Nowadays, argo-workflows is quite mature. I will use argo-workflows for CI part in my future projects. It is definitely worth to invest one’s time on argo-workflow as it is widely used.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>github, action-runner, argo-cd: my cicd pipelines</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2023/02/github-action-runner-argo-cd-my-cicd-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 17:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2023/02/github-action-runner-argo-cd-my-cicd-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>Usually I explain one of my CICD pipeline to others with words such like github action + argo-cd. I am not sure if they understand it. A picture is worth a thousand words. Here is my CICD pipeline picture.
      I used excalidraw to draw the diagram. Excalidraw link is https://excalidraw.com/#json=zJHTTZ_QgcarkYCCankS8,gotb3rzXtE8ux810NoK18A. Feel free to use it.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on my choice of cicd in the past</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/reflection-on-my-choice-of-cicd-in-the-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 20:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/reflection-on-my-choice-of-cicd-in-the-past/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: my CICD choice: argo-cd and argo-workflow
Since I chose argocd and github action as our CICD pipeline two years ago, I rarely thought about other choices and the reason I made the choices. Recently I leant from several sources that jenkins is still widely used, it arouse my interest on this subject again. I reconsidered my choice and layed out the reasons here for my future references.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good impression with java in my past java projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on implementation of CICD using argo-workflows</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/reflection-on-implementation-of-cicd-using-argo-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/reflection-on-implementation-of-cicd-using-argo-workflows/</guid>
      <description>I had some projects on github, gitlab and gitee. Their CI pipelines are quite different. To save the troubles and times, it is a natural choice to seek other options to unify on one solution.
 At first, I looked into jenkins x. However it is quite heavy and with opinions. Considering its Maturity Level Matrix, I am not sure I can make it happen in my limited after hours times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
