<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>certificate on My learning and diary</title>
    <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/certificate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in certificate on My learning and diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 21:01:10 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/certificate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use cert-manager to secure kubernetes cert-manager behind nginx ingress</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/08/use-cert-manager-to-secure-kubernetes-cert-manager-behind-nginx-ingress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 21:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/08/use-cert-manager-to-secure-kubernetes-cert-manager-behind-nginx-ingress/</guid>
      <description>Today I had a case to expose serveral kubernetes dashboard with cert-manager. Initiallly I thought it should be quite easy to setup, but the reality was quite different. My intial yaml is as following.
 apiVersion: networking.k8s.io/v1 kind: Ingress metadata: name: ingress-global-dash namespace: kubernetes-dashboard labels: name: ingress-global-dash use-http01-solver: &amp;#34;true&amp;#34; annotations: cert-manager.io/cluster-issuer: &amp;#34;test-issuer&amp;#34; spec: ingressClassName: nginx rules: - host: &amp;#34;dashboard.example.com&amp;#34; http: paths: - pathType: Prefix path: &amp;#34;/&amp;#34; backend: service: name: kubernetes-dashboard port: number: 80 #later changed to 443 according to port of kubernetes-dashboard svc tls: # &amp;lt; placing a host in the TLS config will determine what ends up in the cert&amp;#39;s subjectAltNames - hosts: - dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add certificates to existing gateway with non-synch resources</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/add-certificates-to-existing-gateway-with-non-synch-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 20:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/add-certificates-to-existing-gateway-with-non-synch-resources/</guid>
      <description>I started one of my certificates using cert-manager and letsencrypt without root domain in one product system. Later I tried to add root domain to the certificate as our customer requested withou success at first day. I figured out how to do that next morning. Here are my the success one and several failed attempts.
 Here some background information of this system: gitops + argocd
 Successful solution Considering that the app argocd is in manual synchronization mode, I can do that changes in place in kubernetes instead of the git repo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
