<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GitOps on My learning and diary</title>
    <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/gitops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GitOps on My learning and diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 17:01:10 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/gitops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do you still need to care ChatOps</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/do-you-still-need-to-care-chatops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 17:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/do-you-still-need-to-care-chatops/</guid>
      <description>ChatOps has its place, even more prominent with AI and rich integration with other systems.
 I learnt ChatOps in the past when I first heard hubot. Later GitOps and Kubernetes grabbed my attention. I didn’t see how ChatOps fit in GitOps until I saw this 湾区日报是如何运作的？ today after I implemented an integration with telegram bot APIs.
 What Are the Benefits of ChatOps? enumerates the benefits. In my eyes I saw other benefits or more benefits in productivity when considing the full potentials of ChatOps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on my choice of cicd in the past</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/reflection-on-my-choice-of-cicd-in-the-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 20:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/reflection-on-my-choice-of-cicd-in-the-past/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: my CICD choice: argo-cd and argo-workflow
Since I chose argocd and github action as our CICD pipeline two years ago, I rarely thought about other choices and the reason I made the choices. Recently I leant from several sources that jenkins is still widely used, it arouse my interest on this subject again. I reconsidered my choice and layed out the reasons here for my future references.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good impression with java in my past java projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on implementation of CICD using argo-workflows</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/reflection-on-implementation-of-cicd-using-argo-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/reflection-on-implementation-of-cicd-using-argo-workflows/</guid>
      <description>I had some projects on github, gitlab and gitee. Their CI pipelines are quite different. To save the troubles and times, it is a natural choice to seek other options to unify on one solution.
 At first, I looked into jenkins x. However it is quite heavy and with opinions. Considering its Maturity Level Matrix, I am not sure I can make it happen in my limited after hours times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>argo-workflow: secrets for git</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/argo-workflow-secrets-for-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/argo-workflow-secrets-for-git/</guid>
      <description>I needed to clone one of my private repositories in one workflow of argo-workflows. I did’t figure a way to mount git artifact into a shared volume at that time. I sought to other options and find https://github.com/argoproj/argo-workflows/issues/1428 and https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2019/mounting-kubernetes-secret-single-file-inside-pod.
 The comment https://github.com/argoproj/argo-workflows/issues/1428#issuecomment-775911838 gives an example to add user name and password into https url. Upon I checked the logs, I found that user and password are shown in the logs of a workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argo-workflows: Generate dynamic json list</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/argo-workflows-generate-dynamic-json-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 12:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/argo-workflows-generate-dynamic-json-list/</guid>
      <description>The journey I worked on a dapr microservice project which need to read a list from a file and do some useful things. Argo-workflow supports loop over a list of items, however one of my steps always got &amp;#34;invalid character &amp;#39;G&amp;#39; looking for beginning of value&amp;#34; before going to next step in the workflow template. The step is as following:
 - name: get-deps inputs: parameters: - name: changes script: image: ubuntu:latest command: [bash] #args: [&amp;#34;echo result was: {{inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
