<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cert-manager on My learning and diary</title>
    <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/cert-manager/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cert-manager on My learning and diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 21:01:10 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/cert-manager/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use cert-manager to secure kubernetes cert-manager behind nginx ingress</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/08/use-cert-manager-to-secure-kubernetes-cert-manager-behind-nginx-ingress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 21:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/08/use-cert-manager-to-secure-kubernetes-cert-manager-behind-nginx-ingress/</guid>
      <description>Today I had a case to expose serveral kubernetes dashboard with cert-manager. Initiallly I thought it should be quite easy to setup, but the reality was quite different. My intial yaml is as following.
 apiVersion: networking.k8s.io/v1 kind: Ingress metadata: name: ingress-global-dash namespace: kubernetes-dashboard labels: name: ingress-global-dash use-http01-solver: &amp;#34;true&amp;#34; annotations: cert-manager.io/cluster-issuer: &amp;#34;test-issuer&amp;#34; spec: ingressClassName: nginx rules: - host: &amp;#34;dashboard.example.com&amp;#34; http: paths: - pathType: Prefix path: &amp;#34;/&amp;#34; backend: service: name: kubernetes-dashboard port: number: 80 #later changed to 443 according to port of kubernetes-dashboard svc tls: # &amp;lt; placing a host in the TLS config will determine what ends up in the cert&amp;#39;s subjectAltNames - hosts: - dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio troubleshooting in new scenario that one service to expose into multiple domains and multiple ingress gateways</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/istio-troubleshooting-in-new-scenario-that-one-service-to-expose-into-multiple-domains-and-multiple-ingress-gateways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 21:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/istio-troubleshooting-in-new-scenario-that-one-service-to-expose-into-multiple-domains-and-multiple-ingress-gateways/</guid>
      <description>Since my first time to configure istio with proxy protocol supports in aws, istio and envoyproxy changed a lot. In the past several days, I was exposed to a different scenario that one service to expose into multiple domains.
 Things are getting not straighforward, I struggled to make it success yesterday. Today another layer of complexity was added into my cluster: an extra ingressgateway for some services.
 For multiple ingress gateways, I followed this article, however my setup is more complex than that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
