<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jsonpath on My learning and diary</title>
    <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/jsonpath/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jsonpath on My learning and diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 20:10:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/jsonpath/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extract multiple fields at different levels of nesting json using chatgpt and jmespath</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/03/extract-multiple-fields-at-different-levels-of-nesting-json-using-chatgpt-and-jmespath/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 20:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/03/extract-multiple-fields-at-different-levels-of-nesting-json-using-chatgpt-and-jmespath/</guid>
      <description>How do you extract multiple fields at different levels of nesting json resources? jsonpath, jq, jmespath or chatgpt?
 In FHIR, bundle resource in json format usually have multiple level of details nested in json. It’s quite different from other use cases.
 My first thought is using jsonpath as it is quite similar to FHIRPath. There are several limitations of jsonpath which make it infeasible.
  It doesn’t support to the use case, even though JsonPath supports deep scan and Bracket-notated child or children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on implementation of CICD using argo-workflows</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/reflection-on-implementation-of-cicd-using-argo-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/reflection-on-implementation-of-cicd-using-argo-workflows/</guid>
      <description>I had some projects on github, gitlab and gitee. Their CI pipelines are quite different. To save the troubles and times, it is a natural choice to seek other options to unify on one solution.
 At first, I looked into jenkins x. However it is quite heavy and with opinions. Considering its Maturity Level Matrix, I am not sure I can make it happen in my limited after hours times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
