<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>postgresql on My learning and diary</title>
    <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/postgresql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in postgresql on My learning and diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 09:10:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/postgresql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Speed up postgresql container without initing everytime</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/10/speed-up-postgresql-container-without-initing-everytime/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 09:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/10/speed-up-postgresql-container-without-initing-everytime/</guid>
      <description>A newly created postgresql container will do a following steps. They are quite time consuming in integration testing and add some unpredictable factor. If a integration testing will clean up tables and data, volumes can be used to speed up postgresql container.
   pg_ctl -D /var/lib/postgresql/data -l logfile start
  initdb
  stop postgresql and start again
   There might be one issue, do I need to maintain the same credential?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things learnt from recent preparation of 1T data for testing</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/10/things-learnt-from-recent-preparation-of-1t-data-for-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 09:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/10/things-learnt-from-recent-preparation-of-1t-data-for-testing/</guid>
      <description>Several things learnt from recent preparation of data for testing.
 Question the way when it takes too long to process data sed: remove last n lines In the past I always thought sed is the fastest way to manipulate data. Is it true for all the cases? I generated 1T testing data in ndjson format, however the last lines of those files are corrupted json data. I had to remove the last line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaceID using customized built postgresql</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/notes/face-identication-postgresql/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 20:40:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/notes/face-identication-postgresql/</guid>
      <description>One of my past projects is based neural network in 2020. The solution is quite simple:
   put the feature vectors into postgresql database
  create distanced based index
   I adopted the model and algrithm from face_recognition, and my team trained on sample faces from our internal system to improve the accuracy to reduce the human involvement and save costs. During development, we found that there is a limit of postgres: CUBE_MAX_DIM, my team customize the build of postgreql to work around the limit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
