<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My learning and diary</title>
    <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My learning and diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 10:01:10 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My first usage of jsonnet</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/my-first-usage-of-jsonnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 10:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/my-first-usage-of-jsonnet/</guid>
      <description>In the past I knew jsonnet, however I didn’t commit too much time to learn it until recently I encountered a data driven scenario, generating istio yaml configurations based on an array of data. The scenario is business driven, and I can foresee that there will be more data coming. What a waste of time to repeat the copy/paste procedures with little tweaks. I hated to do that again and again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add certificates to existing gateway with non-synch resources</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/add-certificates-to-existing-gateway-with-non-synch-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 20:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/add-certificates-to-existing-gateway-with-non-synch-resources/</guid>
      <description>I started one of my certificates using cert-manager and letsencrypt without root domain in one product system. Later I tried to add root domain to the certificate as our customer requested withou success at first day. I figured out how to do that next morning. Here are my the success one and several failed attempts.
 Here some background information of this system: gitops + argocd
 Successful solution Considering that the app argocd is in manual synchronization mode, I can do that changes in place in kubernetes instead of the git repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>recover from mysql XA transaction issues</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/recover-from-mysql-xa-transaction-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 10:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/recover-from-mysql-xa-transaction-issues/</guid>
      <description>In the past 1 week, I encountered an issue that I couldn’t add a column to a table in one of our production database. I thought restart would resolve the issue. After a restart, however the issue still persist. I checked logs in error/mysql-error-running.log in rds and noticed there are two transactions in prepared state after recovery. In the first gooogle search result page, How to Deal with XA Transactions Recovery caught my attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you still need to care ChatOps</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/do-you-still-need-to-care-chatops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 17:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/do-you-still-need-to-care-chatops/</guid>
      <description>ChatOps has its place, even more prominent with AI and rich integration with other systems.
 I learnt ChatOps in the past when I first heard hubot. Later GitOps and Kubernetes grabbed my attention. I didn’t see how ChatOps fit in GitOps until I saw this 湾区日报是如何运作的？ today after I implemented an integration with telegram bot APIs.
 What Are the Benefits of ChatOps? enumerates the benefits. In my eyes I saw other benefits or more benefits in productivity when considing the full potentials of ChatOps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on my choice of cicd in the past</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/reflection-on-my-choice-of-cicd-in-the-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 20:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/reflection-on-my-choice-of-cicd-in-the-past/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: my CICD choice: argo-cd and argo-workflow
Since I chose argocd and github action as our CICD pipeline two years ago, I rarely thought about other choices and the reason I made the choices. Recently I leant from several sources that jenkins is still widely used, it arouse my interest on this subject again. I reconsidered my choice and layed out the reasons here for my future references.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good impression with java in my past java projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio troubleshooting in new scenario that one service to expose into multiple domains and multiple ingress gateways</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/istio-troubleshooting-in-new-scenario-that-one-service-to-expose-into-multiple-domains-and-multiple-ingress-gateways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 21:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/istio-troubleshooting-in-new-scenario-that-one-service-to-expose-into-multiple-domains-and-multiple-ingress-gateways/</guid>
      <description>Since my first time to configure istio with proxy protocol supports in aws, istio and envoyproxy changed a lot. In the past several days, I was exposed to a different scenario that one service to expose into multiple domains.
 Things are getting not straighforward, I struggled to make it success yesterday. Today another layer of complexity was added into my cluster: an extra ingressgateway for some services.
 For multiple ingress gateways, I followed this article, however my setup is more complex than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a S3 bucket public</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/make-a-s3-bucket-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 08:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/make-a-s3-bucket-public/</guid>
      <description>Turn off &amp;#34;Block public access (bucket settings)&amp;#34;        Access control list (ACL): give Everyone (public access) object lists and bucket ACL read.          Policy Policy to attach to a role, so the role can be used to upload resources and put the ACL on the uploaded objects.
 { &amp;#34;Version&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2012-10-17&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Statement&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;Sid&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;VisualEditor0&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Effect&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Allow&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Action&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;s3:ListBucket&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Resource&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;arn:aws:s3:::demo&amp;#34; }, { &amp;#34;Sid&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;VisualEditor1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Effect&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Allow&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Action&amp;#34;: [ &amp;#34;s3:PutObject&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:GetObject&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:DeleteObject&amp;#34; ], &amp;#34;Resource&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;arn:aws:s3:::demo/*&amp;#34; }, { &amp;#34;Sid&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;VisualEditor2&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Effect&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Allow&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Action&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;s3:ListBucket&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Resource&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;arn:aws:s3:::demo-public&amp;#34; }, { &amp;#34;Sid&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;VisualEditor3&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Effect&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Allow&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Action&amp;#34;: [ &amp;#34;s3:PutObject&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:GetObject&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:DeleteObject&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;s3:PutObjectAcl&amp;#34; ], &amp;#34;Resource&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;arn:aws:s3:::demo-public/*&amp;#34; } ] }     Uploading command line bash scripts aws s3 sync --acl public-read local-dir/ s3://demo-public/test/   C# source code using (var client = new AmazonS3Client(RegionEndpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create another user and grant proper permissions in aws rds mysql</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/create-another-user-and-grant-proper-permissions-in-aws-rds-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 16:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/create-another-user-and-grant-proper-permissions-in-aws-rds-mysql/</guid>
      <description>When I tried to create an user for application instead of giving out the master user and its password. I got &amp;#34;Error Code: 1045. Access denied for user &amp;#39;mysqladmin&amp;#39;@&amp;#39;%&amp;#39; (using password: YES)&amp;#34; when I run &amp;#34;GRANT ALL PRIVILEGES ON demodb.* TO &amp;#39;appadmin&amp;#39;@&amp;#39;%&amp;#39;;&amp;#34;.
 I tried the method in How do I create another master user for my Amazon RDS DB instance that is running MySQL?, it is for creating another master user with more permissions than an app db user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>istio virtual service with tls - Connection reset by peer</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/istio-virtual-service-with-tls-connection-reset-by-peer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 11:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/istio-virtual-service-with-tls-connection-reset-by-peer/</guid>
      <description>I got following similar errors when setup my istio clusters.
 Mark bundle as not supporting multiuse 301 istio 301 or 404 error:02FFF036:system library:func(4095):Connection reset by peer * Trying 20.190.14.28:443... * TCP_NODELAY set * Connected to kiali.example.com (20.190.14.28) port 443 (#0) * ALPN, offering http/1.1 * successfully set certificate verify locations: * CAfile: /home/ng/anaconda3/ssl/cacert.pem CApath: none * TLSv1.3 (OUT), TLS handshake, Client hello (1): * OpenSSL SSL_connect: Connection reset by peer in connection to kiali.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on kubernete usage</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/reflection-on-kubernete-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 21:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/reflection-on-kubernete-usage/</guid>
      <description>Today I explained the current infrastructure fleet configurations to our devops team, I have the thought to make a reflection on the things or lessons I learnt in the past and think about what should I do in the next.
 The technologies and tools I used in my projects is as following. There are still a lot of things to learn considering the list in my list and the huge ecosystem of kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resize volumes when PVCs and PVs are okay and the size of file systems in pods doesn&#39;t change</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/resize-volumes-when-pvcs-and-pvs-are-okay-and-the-size-of-file-systems-in-pods-doesnt-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 20:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/resize-volumes-when-pvcs-and-pvs-are-okay-and-the-size-of-file-systems-in-pods-doesnt-change/</guid>
      <description>Here is an issue with aws-ebs-csi-driver: The size of file system doesn’t change when pvc is expanded. I got the same issue when I tried to do the Curl elk in pods to delete indices this afternoon. I got the message &amp;#34;resize2fs 1.44.5 (15-Dec-2018) open: No such file or directory while opening /dev/nvme1n1&amp;#34; as well when I tried to resize the file system /dev/nvme1n1 in my pod.
 As the issue is about csidriver, it is not in the the result of running command &amp;#34;kubectl get csidriver&amp;#34; on my cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curl elk in pods to delete indices</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/curl-elk-in-pods-to-delete-indices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 15:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/curl-elk-in-pods-to-delete-indices/</guid>
      <description>Today my staging kibana didn’t show logs. I made the decision to work out a solution to solve issue in hard way this time. I don’t want me in the same situation without solutoins.
 When things go wrong, you can’t login kibana to do management or maintainance works. The left option is managing the data from the command line. In the past I figured out to use curl cli in pod to get some information of elk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>same device mounted on differences mount points</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/same-device-mounted-on-differences-mount-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 23:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/same-device-mounted-on-differences-mount-points/</guid>
      <description>As in my previous article, I gave the following information of my pod. I still have some time before bed, I couldn’t help to seek the reason of that.
 /usr/share/nginx/html # df -h Filesystem Size Used Available Use% Mounted on overlay 80.0G 34.5G 45.5G 43% / tmpfs 64.0M 0 64.0M 0% /dev tmpfs 3.7G 0 3.7G 0% /sys/fs/cgroup /dev/nvme0n1p1 80.0G 34.5G 45.5G 43% /dev/termination-log /dev/nvme0n1p1 80.0G 34.5G 45.5G 43% /etc/resolv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resize Pod volumes in eks</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/resize-pod-volumes-in-eks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 22:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/resize-pod-volumes-in-eks/</guid>
      <description>I did resize volume of kubernetes in the past, however I encountered an interesting issue when I did the resizing in different way.
 According to doc, I should only change the requested size in pvc. Today I changed the size of pv first, then pvc. Here was the interesting thing: all things of pv and pvc are fine, but the size of the file system in pod was not changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get back my missed keypair of EKS</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/get-back-my-missed-keypair-of-eks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/get-back-my-missed-keypair-of-eks/</guid>
      <description>Today I needed to scale one of my kubernetes clusterss. Those keys are not in my new laptop since I used Mac Air M1. I didn’t see the increase of nodes several minutes after I run the eksctl scale command. I logged into aws console and found there were several &amp;#34;Failed&amp;#34; messages in activity history of the autoscaling group. All the failed messages shown &amp;#34;Launching a new EC2 instance. Status Reason: The aaaa-nodegroup-ng-1-67:8e:b8:8e:33:83:93:68 key pair does not exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio Envoy passthrough goes wrong when port 80 are used for SMTP protocol instead of standard ports</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/istio-envoy-passthrough-goes-wrong-when-port-80-are-used-for-smtp-protocol-instead-of-standard-ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 17:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/istio-envoy-passthrough-goes-wrong-when-port-80-are-used-for-smtp-protocol-instead-of-standard-ports/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this on September 7, 2021 and published it on linkedin. However I found that it can be hard to search if I put there. so I put here anoter copy
 TLDR: if your external SMTP is using port 80 instead of standard ports in an istio mesh, create a Service Entry for the external SMTP.
 These two days, a strange timeout issue happened in one of our kubernetes clusters when trying to send emails via SMTP even though the same configuration works perfectly on our development machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes and immutable infrastructure: docker image digest and image labels</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/kubernetes-and-immutable-infrastructure-docker-image-digest-and-image-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 19:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/kubernetes-and-immutable-infrastructure-docker-image-digest-and-image-labels/</guid>
      <description>Summary: use digest as the way to refer to docker images in kubernetes resources, put commit id in image labels.
 An idempotency and immutable infrastructure has a slew of benefits. I am a firm believer of it and I did my best to keep several projects in that way. In the past few weeks, I helped one friend to resolve system structure, performance issue and development experience of one of his projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>projected volumes in argo-workflow</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/projected-volumes-in-argo-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/projected-volumes-in-argo-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I added gitconfig volume and mounted to /root. However today the logs of the workflow shows netrc is mounted to /root as well. They are conflicted. Kubernetes supports projected volume which supports following types. my netrc and gitconfig are in the list.
   secret
  downwardAPI
  configMap
  serviceAccountToken
   I made the small tweak to hello world sample workflow. Here is the my demo workflow with projected volumes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First trial mermaid Diagrams in hugo</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/first-trial-mermaid-diagrams-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/first-trial-mermaid-diagrams-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Since I read the textual UML in the 2015 techradar, I am a big fan of it. I used plantuml in my technical writing in Asia Fusion Technology. Later I found asciidoc, and I wanted to combine the two together. I regularly read techradar from thoughtworks and found mermaidjs in NOV 2018 techradar. However it was little hard to integrate that into my site at that time. Today I knew Hugo supports Mermaid Diagrams easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>docker buildx multi-context, multi-platform, multi-stage and secrets in action</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/docker-buildx-multi-context-multi-platform-multi-stage-and-secrets-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/docker-buildx-multi-context-multi-platform-multi-stage-and-secrets-in-action/</guid>
      <description>Prologue Today I migrated several golang projects to golang 1.18. I had several hiccups today. Let’s called docker buildx multi-context, multi-platform, multi-stage and secrets in action.
   Multi-platform I started to look into one iOS and android app of our projects one week ago, and started to use Mac Air M1. Mac Air M1 is arm64 based, however our production environment is amd64 based. I had to do some changes to make the images built on my or my colleagues&amp;#39; machine can be runnable in production environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on implementation of CICD using argo-workflows</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/reflection-on-implementation-of-cicd-using-argo-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/reflection-on-implementation-of-cicd-using-argo-workflows/</guid>
      <description>I had some projects on github, gitlab and gitee. Their CI pipelines are quite different. To save the troubles and times, it is a natural choice to seek other options to unify on one solution.
 At first, I looked into jenkins x. However it is quite heavy and with opinions. Considering its Maturity Level Matrix, I am not sure I can make it happen in my limited after hours times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>argo-workflow: secrets for git</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/argo-workflow-secrets-for-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/argo-workflow-secrets-for-git/</guid>
      <description>I needed to clone one of my private repositories in one workflow of argo-workflows. I did’t figure a way to mount git artifact into a shared volume at that time. I sought to other options and find https://github.com/argoproj/argo-workflows/issues/1428 and https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2019/mounting-kubernetes-secret-single-file-inside-pod.
 The comment https://github.com/argoproj/argo-workflows/issues/1428#issuecomment-775911838 gives an example to add user name and password into https url. Upon I checked the logs, I found that user and password are shown in the logs of a workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argo-event filters: expr filter in action</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/argo-event-filters-expr-filter-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/argo-event-filters-expr-filter-in-action/</guid>
      <description>Today I found my argo-events sensor executed triggers which I was not intended to. In the logs, I found that ref fields of those non-intended triggers all started with &amp;#34;refs/heads/dev&amp;#34;. I checked again with document and found this surprising truth:
 https://argoproj.github.io/argo-events/sensors/filters/data/#:~:text=If%20data%20type%20is%20string%2C%20you%20can%20pass%20either%20an%20exact%20value%20or%20a%20regex.%20In%20any%20case%20that%20value%20will%20be%20evaluated%20as%20a%20regex.
 If data type is string, you can pass either an exact value or a regex. In any case that value will be evaluated as a regex.   Considing my following data filter, no wonder it triggers more than I expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workaround the limitation of authorization header of webhook in argo-events</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/workaround-the-limitation-of-authorization-header-of-webhook-in-argo-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/workaround-the-limitation-of-authorization-header-of-webhook-in-argo-events/</guid>
      <description>Webhook of argo-events supports authentication, however the field is fixed in header. If your callers don’t do that way, you are screwed. Recently days, I was trying to integrate gitee with argo-workflow and argo-events. I hit the wall here.
 TOKEN=&amp;#34;Bearer af3qqs321f2ddwf1e2e67dfda3fs&amp;#34; curl -X POST -H &amp;#34;Authorization: $TOKEN&amp;#34; -d &amp;#34;{your data}&amp;#34; http://xxxxx:12000/example   I kept reading the documents for serveral days and the knowledge sinked in, I got the idea that filters maybe can be used for that as a workaround solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup bluetooth mouses in mac air with three not-existing devices</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/setup-bluetooth-mouses-in-mac-air-with-three-not-existing-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/setup-bluetooth-mouses-in-mac-air-with-three-not-existing-devices/</guid>
      <description>I heard from my colleagues that MacAir M1 is picky about mice and you can find many threads in reddit about this if you use the keywords &amp;#34;reddit mac air m1 mouse issues bluetooth&amp;#34; to search. Today is my lucky day, I encountered the issue too.
 This morning, I brought my Mac Air to office and used the mouse of company. The bluethooth kept spinning and the mouse can’t connect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup dapr on AWS and calico</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/setup-dapr-on-aws-and-calico/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/setup-dapr-on-aws-and-calico/</guid>
      <description>Low resource usage Our system had low resource usage, however my several pods got stucked in ContainerCreating state. Kubernetes events show that &amp;#34;add cmd: failed to assign an IP address to container&amp;#34;. &amp;#34;kubectl top nodes&amp;#34; still shows the usage of resources still low.
 jackl@LAPTOP-IIHUF2DR:~$ k --context jack.l@test-dev.ap-southeast-1.eksctl.io top nodes NAME CPU(cores) CPU% MEMORY(bytes) MEMORY% ip-192-168-102-109.ap-southeast-1.compute.internal 143m 7% 3217Mi 45% ip-192-168-110-171.ap-southeast-1.compute.internal 117m 6% 2892Mi 41%     Migrate to calico  Recreate cluster without nodegroups</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argo-workflows: Generate dynamic json list</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/argo-workflows-generate-dynamic-json-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 12:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/argo-workflows-generate-dynamic-json-list/</guid>
      <description>The journey I worked on a dapr microservice project which need to read a list from a file and do some useful things. Argo-workflow supports loop over a list of items, however one of my steps always got &amp;#34;invalid character &amp;#39;G&amp;#39; looking for beginning of value&amp;#34; before going to next step in the workflow template. The step is as following:
 - name: get-deps inputs: parameters: - name: changes script: image: ubuntu:latest command: [bash] #args: [&amp;#34;echo result was: {{inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich link preview and IM apps</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/rich-link-preview-and-im-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 19:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/rich-link-preview-and-im-apps/</guid>
      <description>Two days ago, I have a fun journey to find more about rich link preview features in social media, web apps and IM apps.
 The journey began with that the shared link of one of my company sites in skype was shown without pictures, just a plain link. Searching the feature of skype &amp;#34;link preview&amp;#34;, I found https://socialsharepreview.com/. I knew what missed in the homepage as in the following list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My blogging journey</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/my-blogging-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 19:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/my-blogging-journey/</guid>
      <description>Usually I don’t want to blog about something, espicially I don’t contribute some original things to internet. Of couse, there are other reasons as well.
 There were many reasons which stopped me in the past to writing. One was that my vocabulary was limited. I started my blogging actitivies back to 2004. At that time, my vocabulary was limited, I think the size of my vocabulary was in the range from 6000-7000 and most words were memorized in isolated way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I migrate my blog from Jekyll to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/why-i-migrate-my-blog-from-jekyll-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/why-i-migrate-my-blog-from-jekyll-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I wrote my blogs using Jekyll at this domain almost two years occasionally from 2018 until 2020. I didn’t think to move to Hugo before it was used in one of my company project. After two or three weeks since the project kicked off, I had a thought why not move to Hugo considering several benefits.
 For the uninitiated, Hugo is one of the most popular open-source static site generators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A strange issue of kubernetes: New pod kept in CrashloopBackOff in newly joined node.</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/a-strange-issue-of-kubernetes-new-pod-kept-in-crashloopbackoff-in-newly-joined-node./</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 21:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/a-strange-issue-of-kubernetes-new-pod-kept-in-crashloopbackoff-in-newly-joined-node./</guid>
      <description>Today I encountered a strange issue with one kubernete cluster. Newly created pods are not created on a newly joined node. There is no errors in logs of pods and the node, events of kubernete. All seems normal. I created a simple nginx pod with nodeName as the problematic node. The pod can be scheduled and created in the node. However the pod was kept in CrashloopBackOff state. There is definitely something wrong with server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup vscode development for dapr in WSL</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/04/setup-vscode-development-for-dapr-in-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 19:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/04/setup-vscode-development-for-dapr-in-wsl/</guid>
      <description>Dapr development is quite difficult to setup correctly. You can get the idea from (this issue) as the issue is still open now since it was created.
 I followed the instruction to install dapr vs code extension in dapr. My environment is WSL based. I tried several times to try to debug the dapr applications and failed. I noticed in the following screenshot that there was a warning icon before kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run a flutter app on Windows Subsystem for Android</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/04/run-a-flutter-app-on-windows-subsystem-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 19:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/04/run-a-flutter-app-on-windows-subsystem-for-android/</guid>
      <description>Keep WSA running WSA seems sometimes will exit after a while idle time. I need to run the following command to keep it running.
 adb connect YOUR_IP_ADDRESS     Run App According to How to use Windows Subsystem for Android as a development tool, there are several ways to run flutter apps in WSA.
 Android studio When I try to run a project of my company in Android studio, I kept get the error &amp;#34;An unexpected packet was received before the handshake&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on the usage of bazel</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/04/reflection-on-the-usage-of-bazel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 19:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/04/reflection-on-the-usage-of-bazel/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: Bazel is definitely worth to use on your projects even though it has minimum supports of some languages such as C#.
   Prologue Before I was interested in bazel, I always thought why bother to learn a new building system even I knew that kubernetes once was built with bazel. 4 months ago, I was involved in a micro service structured project. I was dissatisfied with dev workflow using skaffold and I looked other options in the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Windows Subsystem for Android</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/04/install-windows-subsystem-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 19:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/04/install-windows-subsystem-for-android/</guid>
      <description>Install WAS  Upgrade to windows 11 latest version (GA, Preview, Evaluation etc).
  Upgrade microsoft appstore to latest version
  Setting→Time &amp;amp; Language → Langage &amp;amp; Region → Region: USA
  Open AppStore, Search Amazon Appstore and install Amazon Appstore. it will install Windows Subsystem for Android as well.
     Install applications as user using Amazon AppStore  Register as Amazon US user</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure action runner in eks&#43;calico environment</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/02/configure-action-runner-in-eks-calico-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 13:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/02/configure-action-runner-in-eks-calico-environment/</guid>
      <description>Last week I setup our staging kubernetes environment, however the once worked version of runnerset yaml configuration didn’t work. I tried different combination of controller and summerwind/actions-runner-dind image, fully customized template portion with RUNNER_xxx arguments. I still got &amp;#34;Http response code: NotFound from &amp;#39;POST https://api.github.com/actions/runner-registration&amp;#39;&amp;#34; for every combination of those combinations in the logs of runner pods. I thought RunnerDeployment is stateless and less complex than RunnerSet. I gave it a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply proxy protocol listener filters to specific ports in istio</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/08/apply-proxy-protocol-listener-filters-to-specific-ports-in-istio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 09:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/08/apply-proxy-protocol-listener-filters-to-specific-ports-in-istio/</guid>
      <description>Two days ago, our web applications need to get clients&amp;#39; real IP address. Our sites is hosted in kubernetes, isito is used for ingress controll. behind cloud load balancers, it is not easy to make it work.
 There are two ways to do that in alibaba classic load balancer: http/https listeners, and TCP listeners with proxy protocol
 HTTPS listeners is crossed out due to certificate issue. HTTPS listeners can use integrated certificates or self uploaded certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup opencv in windows</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/04/setup-opencv-in-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 11:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/04/setup-opencv-in-windows/</guid>
      <description> Download opencv release package https://github.com/opencv/opencv/releases/download/4.5.2/opencv-4.5.2-vc14_vc15.exe
  run the downloaded executable, and say install it at c:\software\opencv
  run opencv\build\setup_vars_opencv4.cmd
   After above steps, your environment is ready. However there is a caveat, the environment is ephemeral.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup softHSM2</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/04/setup-softhsm2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 16:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/04/setup-softhsm2/</guid>
      <description>Secrets Management is the strong suit of Hashicorp vault. Open source edition is little limited comparing to cloud and enterprise edition, and cloud and enterprise editions sometimes are not allowed due to some reasons. bank-vaults seems a promising solution based on open source edition of Hashicorp Vault.
 Advanced usage of vault will involve HSM and SoftHSM is good start point without spending several hundards bucks. Besides, HSM is widely used in Financial sector, blockchain and cryptocurrency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install calico cni in alicloud ack and advanced dns troubleshooting in kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/03/install-calico-cni-in-alicloud-ack-and-advanced-dns-troubleshooting-in-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 19:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/03/install-calico-cni-in-alicloud-ack-and-advanced-dns-troubleshooting-in-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>2 weeks I started to learn alicloud to prepare the migration from aws to alicloud. I started the migration this week. Our applications are deployed on kubernetes, I focused on ACK first. The setup journey was bumpy, and most of the issues can be resolved by googling and trial loops. The most difficult one is that dns resolution issue.
 I tried the steps in &amp;#34;Debugging DNS Resolution&amp;#34; [1]. All steps were good except the nslookup step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposing TCP and UDP services in nginx ingress</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/03/exposing-tcp-and-udp-services-in-nginx-ingress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 17:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/03/exposing-tcp-and-udp-services-in-nginx-ingress/</guid>
      <description>Add command line flags in ingress controller:  --tcp-services-configmap
  --udp-services-configmap
     Create configmap apiVersion: v1 kind: ConfigMap metadata: name: tcp-services namespace: ingress-nginx data: 5432: &amp;#34;default/postgres:5432&amp;#34;     Patch the ingress-nginx-controller to allow port 5432 spec: template: spec: containers: - name: controller ports: - containerPort: 6379 hostPort: 6379     Add inbound rule to security group of node groups   Reference: https://minikube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Grey market dynamic</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/02/stock-grey-market-dynamic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 11:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/02/stock-grey-market-dynamic/</guid>
      <description>Here are the grey market dynamics trading kuaishou in futu and first day in stock. Don’t be gready. Most likely the professional/instutional traders in grey market outsmart you, they don’t leave profit margin for you considering the dynamic in first day trading.
         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nginx ingress and SPA sites</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/01/nginx-ingress-and-spa-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 21:53:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/01/nginx-ingress-and-spa-sites/</guid>
      <description>Several months ago, I resolved the issue &amp;#34;404 Error on refresh with SPA&amp;#34; by using nginx try_files directive, this time it was quite different as the apps were deployed into kubernetes. I tried nginx.ingress.kubernetes.io/use-regex:true and nginx.ingress.kubernetes.io/rewrite-target: /$1. To avoid to block others to others to use staging environment, I setup an skaffold local development environment to troubeshooting the issue. I tried following annotation as well.
 nginx.ingress.kubernetes.io/configuration-snippet: | try_files $uri $uri/ /index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vega in hugo</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/01/vega-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 15:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/01/vega-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description> var spec = &#39;https:\/\/raw.githubusercontent.com\/vega\/vega\/master\/docs\/examples\/bar-chart.vg.json&#39;; vegaEmbed(&#39;#viz&#39;, spec).then(function(result) { }).catch(console.error);   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>echarts in hugo</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/01/echarts-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 14:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/01/echarts-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>var myChart = echarts.init(document.getElementById(&#39;echarts400&#39;)); var option = JSON.parse(&#34;\n {\n \&#34;textStyle\&#34;:{\n \&#34;color\&#34;:\&#34;#fff\&#34;\n },\n \&#34;title\&#34;:{\n \&#34;text\&#34;:\&#34;2018年11月国内浏览器数据统计\&#34;,\n \&#34;subtext\&#34;:\&#34;浏览器数据分析\&#34;,\n \&#34;x\&#34;:\&#34;center\&#34;,\n \&#34;textStyle\&#34;:{\n \&#34;color\&#34;:\&#34;#FFffFf\&#34;\n }\n },\n \&#34;tooltip\&#34;:{\n \&#34;trigger\&#34;:\&#34;item\&#34;,\n \&#34;formatter\&#34;:\&#34;{a} \u003cbr/\u003e{b} : {c} ({d}%)\&#34;\n },\n \&#34;legend\&#34;:{\n \&#34;type\&#34;:\&#34;scroll\&#34;,\n \&#34;orient\&#34;:\&#34;vertical\&#34;,\n \&#34;right\&#34;:10,\n \&#34;top\&#34;:120,\n \&#34;bottom\&#34;:20,\n \&#34;data\&#34;:[\n \&#34;Chrome\&#34;,\n \&#34;IE 9.0\&#34;,\n \&#34;IE 11.0\&#34;,\n \&#34;QQ\&#34;,\n \&#34;IE 8.0\&#34;,\n \&#34;2345\&#34;,\n \&#34;搜狗高速\&#34;,\n \&#34;Firefox\&#34;,\n \&#34;Safari\&#34;,\n \&#34;其他\&#34;\n ],\n \&#34;textStyle\&#34;:{\n \&#34;color\&#34;:\&#34;#fff\&#34;\n }\n },\n \&#34;series\&#34;:[\n {\n \&#34;name\&#34;:\&#34;浏览器用户比例\&#34;,\n \&#34;type\&#34;:\&#34;pie\&#34;,\n \&#34;radius\&#34;:\&#34;55%\&#34;,\n \&#34;center\&#34;:[\n \&#34;50%\&#34;,\n \&#34;60%\&#34;\n ],\n \&#34;data\&#34;:[\n {\n \&#34;name\&#34;:\&#34;Chrome\&#34;,\n \&#34;value\&#34;:46.88\n },\n {\n \&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>log to stdin of a pod in nested shells</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/12/log-to-stdin-of-a-pod-in-nested-shells/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 10:35:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/12/log-to-stdin-of-a-pod-in-nested-shells/</guid>
      <description>During practicing the lifecycle handlers of pod, I found it is quite difficult to get the logs logged from preStop handlers. Initially I thought terminationMessagePath maybe is the answer, but no such luck. The preStop handler will be run before the pod is deleted. After deleted, there is no way to get the logs unless those logs are kept in other place such as central log servers etc. Those settings are way complex for a simple practice and time-consuming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vscode debug python containers running kubernetes via attachment</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/11/vscode-debug-python-containers-running-kubernetes-via-attachment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 19:35:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/11/vscode-debug-python-containers-running-kubernetes-via-attachment/</guid>
      <description>python-guestbook at https://github.com/GoogleCloudPlatform/cloud-code-samples is used to practice debug python containers in kubernetes.
 Google cloud python code vscode plugin 1.7.0 failed to run python on kubernetes or there is no obvious way to do that as depicted in the below pic.      Steps to make it:
  run
skaffold debug     Import ptvsd in the python file to debug, add breakout() before the line to debug</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jetbrain debug containers in kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/11/jetbrain-debug-containers-in-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 13:35:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/11/jetbrain-debug-containers-in-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>I can’t debug the dockerdev app following the steps in https://blog.jetbrains.com/go/2020/05/11/using-kubernetes-from-goland/, even after I cloned its source code https://github.com/jackliusr/dockerdev/tree/kubernetes-debug.
 I read several articles before I tried the aboved one. The successful debug after several trial and errors. I added skaffold.yaml to the project and installed Cloud Code. skaffold.yaml can be found at https://github.com/jackliusr/dockerdev/tree/kubernetes-debug. Other jetbrain configuration can be seen in the below pictures.
          cloud code is a very good tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a new way to anti scrapping</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/10/a-new-way-to-anti-scrapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 18:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/10/a-new-way-to-anti-scrapping/</guid>
      <description>I loved to read novels. Recently I found that several sites show some garbed characters in square boxes. I went to the original site qidian and those chacters are shown correctly in the orignal site. After little investigation, I found the following information;
          In above pics, 了’s HTML entity code is , it is not as 天.
 How does chrome show the characters correctly?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup kubeflow pipeline on local KIND cluster</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/10/setup-kubeflow-pipeline-on-local-kind-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 10:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/10/setup-kubeflow-pipeline-on-local-kind-cluster/</guid>
      <description># https://www.kubeflow.org/docs/pipelines/installation/localcluster-deployment/#deploying-kubeflow-pipelines # env/platform-agnostic-pns hasn&amp;#39;t been publically released, so we install from master temporarily export PIPELINE_VERSION=1.0.1 kubectl apply -k &amp;#34;github.com/kubeflow/pipelines/manifests/kustomize/cluster-scoped-resources?ref=$PIPELINE_VERSION&amp;#34; kubectl wait --for condition=established --timeout=60s crd/applications.app.k8s.io kubectl apply -k &amp;#34;github.com/kubeflow/pipelines/manifests/kustomize/env/platform-agnostic-pns?ref=$PIPELINE_VERSION&amp;#34; # expose gui kubectl port-forward -n kubeflow --address 0.0.0.0 svc/ml-pipeline-ui 8080:80   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a multiple-nodes KIND kubernetes cluster</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/09/create-a-multiple-nodes-kind-kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 22:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/09/create-a-multiple-nodes-kind-kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>KIND supports configuration items and you can find them at https://kind.sigs.k8s.io/docs/user/configuration. Following is the outline of the doc.
 Cluster-Wide Options ︎ Networking: ︎ IP Family ︎ API Server: port and listen address Pod Subnet ︎ Service Subnet ︎ Disable Default CNI: can be used to try other CNI for CKA and CKAD networks kube-proxy mode : iptables, ipvs Nodes: role control-plane, worker Per-Node Options ︎ Extra Mounts ︎ Extra Port Mappings ︎ Kubeadm Config Patches: Kubeadm Config Patches, kubeadm InitConfiguration and JoinConfiguration   My asciicast is as following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pod CrashLoopBackOff Reason</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/09/pod-crashloopbackoff-reason/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 08:51:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/09/pod-crashloopbackoff-reason/</guid>
      <description>Today one of my deployments always got CrashLoopBackOff. Searching internet don’t gave me the root cause of those errors even I went through all the steps. Steps from internets are all about describe, logs, liveProbe etc. I noticed the reason and exit code in last state when I described one of the pod. It should be the focus point to find root cause of CrashBoopBackOff.
 Containers: nginx: Container ID: containerd://9570e7e67d83692fdbe0e0871919a81222137fcaee2eaecb1eff6b772ec805b1 Image: nginx:1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first post</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/08/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 18:12:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/08/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is my first adoc post after migration from jekyll to hugo.
   a
  b
  test
   order list testing
  a
  b
   third try to test github action
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I stick to jekyll</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/08/why-i-stick-to-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/08/why-i-stick-to-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>I am a big fan of Tex and asciidoc. Asciidoctor is ruby based and can been easily integrated into jekyll. Hugo currently still has some rough edges in asciidoc integration. Considering the time and effort to switch to Hugo, it is not worth to do that.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>run redux-saga examples</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/07/run-redux-saga-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/07/run-redux-saga-examples/</guid>
      <description>run redux-saga examples TL;DR:
 yarn yarn build
 I run into module not found issues when I try to run those examples under the repository of redus-saga. Even following comments in github issues and stackoverflow, those solutions don’t work out.
 Scripts in the package.json of the root folder don’t work for examples.
 After run yarn &amp;amp;&amp;amp; yarn build, can change directories to those examples and run them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workaround solution for inout refcursor parameters for stored procedure in postgresql 11 JDBC</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/12/workaround-solution-for-inout-refcursor-parameters-for-stored-procedure-in-postgresql-11-jdbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/12/workaround-solution-for-inout-refcursor-parameters-for-stored-procedure-in-postgresql-11-jdbc/</guid>
      <description>The workaround solution mentioned at Issue doesn’t work when inout refcursor parameter is used.
 Here is my workaround solution for that.
 CREATE OR REPLACE PROCEDURE sp_test(INOUT results refcursor) LANGUAGE plpgsql SECURITY DEFINER AS $procedure$ begin results := &amp;#39;cur&amp;#39; ; OPEN results for select generate_series dt from generate_series(date&amp;#39;2019-01-01&amp;#39; , date&amp;#39;2019-01-31&amp;#39;, interval &amp;#39;1 day&amp;#39;); end;$procedure$ ;   conn.setAutoCommit(false); Statement st = conn.createStatement(); ResultSet rs0 = st.executeQuery(&amp;#34;call sp_test(&amp;#39;&amp;#39;)&amp;#34;); ResultSet rs = st.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error message of rabbitmq is terrible</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/03/error-message-of-rabbitmq-is-terrible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/03/error-message-of-rabbitmq-is-terrible/</guid>
      <description>Error message of rabbitmq is terrible Today I installed RabbitMQ 3.7.13-1. However I always got the following messages when running rabbitmq-server and a dump. The error message doesn’t give any clue of root cause. It is none of the cases searched from google such as permission issue, configuration issue etc.
 {&amp;#34;init terminating in do_boot&amp;#34;,{undef,[{rabbit_prelaunch,start,[],[]},{init,start_em,1,[]},{init,do_boot,3,[]}]}}   I re-read the installation guide and double-checked steps and configuration. There is no luck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issues of clean setup spacemacs and their solutions</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/issues-of-clean-setup-spacemacs-and-their-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/issues-of-clean-setup-spacemacs-and-their-solutions/</guid>
      <description>I encountered the same issue &amp;#34;File error: Cannot open load file, No such file or directory, bind-map&amp;#34; twice in my setup of spacemacs. The issue can be solved several ways which I found from github and clojurians-log.clojureverse.org. I consolidate the reasons and list them below.
   Timeout: the relevant setting in .spacemacs :- dotspacemacs-elpa-timeout 30
  TLS Certs: emacs --insecure
  Permanent TLS Certs: the relevant setting in .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Bonding</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/chemical-bonding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/chemical-bonding/</guid>
      <description>Chemical Bonding The Stable Electronic configuration of a noble gas An outer electron or outermost electron is also known as valence electron. Only outer electrons are involved in chemical reactions.
 In what way do noble gases behave differently from other chemistry ? Noble gases are unreactive because they have fully filled outer shells, that is, they have duplet or octet electronic configuration.
 How do atom achieve the electronic configuration of a noble gas?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic Particle Theory</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/kinetic-particle-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 20:20:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/kinetic-particle-theory/</guid>
      <description>States of Matter Matter is substance that has mass and occupies space. All living and non-living things are matter.
 State of matter: solid, liquid, gas
     Property Solid Liquid Gas     Shape
 fixed
 not fixed
 not fixed
   Volume
 fixed
 fixed
 not fixed
   Compressibility
 Cannot be compressed
 cannot be compressed</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math jax testing</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/math-jax-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 20:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/math-jax-testing/</guid>
      <description>The difference of two squared numbers
 $ a^2 - b^2 = (a + b )(a - b) $
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Structure</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/atomic-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/atomic-structure/</guid>
      <description>Inside Atoms All matter is made up of atoms. Atoms are made up of subatomic particles: protons, neutrons and electrons.
 The protons and neutrons
   are tightly packed in the centre of an atom
  together from the nucleus of the atom.
   The electrons move rapidly around the nucleus.
     Subatomic particle Symbol Relative charge Relative mass     Inside the nucleus</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Klipse</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/integration-of-klipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/02/integration-of-klipse/</guid>
      <description>(+ 1 2 3 4 5)   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twilio Call Status StateChart</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/01/twilio-call-status-statechart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/01/twilio-call-status-statechart/</guid>
      <description>I was not familiar with SIP states during the integration of VoIP products such as twilio, plivo and sinch. I am still confused about the state changes after reading documents. Here try to visualize the state change and help me to remember it. The state chart is based on my understanding. It is not necessarily correct. It is just for my reference.
 QueuedInitiatedRingingAnsweredInProgressCompletedBusyNoAnswerCanceledFailed   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit 1: Experimental Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/01/unit-1-experimental-chemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/01/unit-1-experimental-chemistry/</guid>
      <description>Measurement     Physical properties
 SI Units
 Other Common Units
 Common measuring apparatus
   Name
 Symbol
   time
 second
 s
   hour (h)
  minutes(min)
  day
     digital stopwatch
  analogue stopwatch
     mass
 kilogram
 kg
   gram(g)
  tonne(t)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asciidoc diagram  samples of UML</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/01/asciidoc-diagram-samples-of-uml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/01/asciidoc-diagram-samples-of-uml/</guid>
      <description>PlantUML Diagram Class diagram—​Relations between Class:
     Type
 Sysmbol
   Extension
 &amp;lt;!--
   Composition
 *--
   Aggregation
 o--
    Asciidoc UML sample
 Class01Class02Class03Class04Class05Class06Class07Class08Class09Class10   PlantUML sample
 Class01Class02Class03Class04Class05Class06Class07Class08Class09Class10     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asynchronization is hard to implement</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/01/asynchronization-is-hard-to-implement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/01/asynchronization-is-hard-to-implement/</guid>
      <description>Asynchronization is very hard. It brings benefits with several catches for backend programming. Here is serveral catches and respective solutions. However all those will increase the cost of developments.
   Hard to debug and trace As the process breaks down to serveral asynchronious subprocesses, it is very difficult to relate all information of the process when something goes wrong. An extra overhead correlation Id is needed to adopt to ameliorate this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I start to write again</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/01/why-i-start-to-write-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2019/01/why-i-start-to-write-again/</guid>
      <description>I read a lot of blogs. However I rarely wrote my blogs about my thoughts and learning experiences as I thought those are lack of originality.
 I changed my mind after I learned more than ten thousand words using anki and memrise in the past 2 years. A writing can serve multiple purposes even lack of originality and thorough thought. Here is a list of those purposes:
   Deepen my understanding in the topics and improve efficiency of learning</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagrams samples</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2018/12/diagrams-samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2018/12/diagrams-samples/</guid>
      <description>Ditaa
 0 start1 q scans from start to end.....endrest of theallocated memory.....n    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
