<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>istio on My learning and diary</title>
    <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/istio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in istio on My learning and diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 21:01:10 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/istio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Istio troubleshooting in new scenario that one service to expose into multiple domains and multiple ingress gateways</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/istio-troubleshooting-in-new-scenario-that-one-service-to-expose-into-multiple-domains-and-multiple-ingress-gateways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 21:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/istio-troubleshooting-in-new-scenario-that-one-service-to-expose-into-multiple-domains-and-multiple-ingress-gateways/</guid>
      <description>Since my first time to configure istio with proxy protocol supports in aws, istio and envoyproxy changed a lot. In the past several days, I was exposed to a different scenario that one service to expose into multiple domains.
 Things are getting not straighforward, I struggled to make it success yesterday. Today another layer of complexity was added into my cluster: an extra ingressgateway for some services.
 For multiple ingress gateways, I followed this article, however my setup is more complex than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>istio virtual service with tls - Connection reset by peer</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/istio-virtual-service-with-tls-connection-reset-by-peer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 11:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/06/istio-virtual-service-with-tls-connection-reset-by-peer/</guid>
      <description>I got following similar errors when setup my istio clusters.
 Mark bundle as not supporting multiuse 301 istio 301 or 404 error:02FFF036:system library:func(4095):Connection reset by peer * Trying 20.190.14.28:443... * TCP_NODELAY set * Connected to kiali.example.com (20.190.14.28) port 443 (#0) * ALPN, offering http/1.1 * successfully set certificate verify locations: * CAfile: /home/ng/anaconda3/ssl/cacert.pem CApath: none * TLSv1.3 (OUT), TLS handshake, Client hello (1): * OpenSSL SSL_connect: Connection reset by peer in connection to kiali.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio Envoy passthrough goes wrong when port 80 are used for SMTP protocol instead of standard ports</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/istio-envoy-passthrough-goes-wrong-when-port-80-are-used-for-smtp-protocol-instead-of-standard-ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 17:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/05/istio-envoy-passthrough-goes-wrong-when-port-80-are-used-for-smtp-protocol-instead-of-standard-ports/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this on September 7, 2021 and published it on linkedin. However I found that it can be hard to search if I put there. so I put here anoter copy
 TLDR: if your external SMTP is using port 80 instead of standard ports in an istio mesh, create a Service Entry for the external SMTP.
 These two days, a strange timeout issue happened in one of our kubernetes clusters when trying to send emails via SMTP even though the same configuration works perfectly on our development machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply proxy protocol listener filters to specific ports in istio</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/08/apply-proxy-protocol-listener-filters-to-specific-ports-in-istio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 09:10:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2021/08/apply-proxy-protocol-listener-filters-to-specific-ports-in-istio/</guid>
      <description>Two days ago, our web applications need to get clients&amp;#39; real IP address. Our sites is hosted in kubernetes, isito is used for ingress controll. behind cloud load balancers, it is not easy to make it work.
 There are two ways to do that in alibaba classic load balancer: http/https listeners, and TCP listeners with proxy protocol
 HTTPS listeners is crossed out due to certificate issue. HTTPS listeners can use integrated certificates or self uploaded certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
