<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>javascript on My learning and diary</title>
    <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in javascript on My learning and diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 20:10:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MACH (micro service based, API first, cloud native, headless)</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/06/mach-micro-service-based-api-first-cloud-native-headless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 20:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/06/mach-micro-service-based-api-first-cloud-native-headless/</guid>
      <description>Just an architecture style MACH got me attention. It is short for micro service based, API first, cloud native, headless. There are two of projects I involved one are in this architecture style. One is sitecore based, another one is developed. Kubernetes, nodejs, npm, strapi tsoa are used. Their mapping is as following.
   micro services based: multiple services based on expressjs
  api first: tsao
  cloud native: more advanced than cloud native, kubernate native is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using copilot for javascript debugging</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/04/using-copilot-for-javascript-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 20:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/04/using-copilot-for-javascript-debugging/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I clicked a button in one web page, no response from that. I thought it must be something wrong. I opened browser console and noticed there is an icon. It turned out be a copilot icon after reading the logs in console.
      Nowadays, copilot almost is everywhere, office suite, vscode, visual studio, windows and edge browser. Never thought it is embedded in browse web console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract multiple field and values from a json file fetched once in powerquery</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/02/extract-multiple-field-and-values-from-a-json-file-fetched-once-in-powerquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 23:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/02/extract-multiple-field-and-values-from-a-json-file-fetched-once-in-powerquery/</guid>
      <description>I learnt to extract npm package inform from https://registry.npmjs.org/ on 2023-08-31. Today I have more packages. The original query need to be optimized for better performance.
 In the old post, one can quickly spot that the package information is fetched twice. It is the place to optimize today. I will put selected fields into a column, and extract values from the column later. This way, It can spend less time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get information from internet in excel, custom function vs powerquery</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2023/08/get-information-from-internet-in-excel-custom-function-vs-powerquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2023/08/get-information-from-internet-in-excel-custom-function-vs-powerquery/</guid>
      <description>Last week I worked on filling info package information to a workbooks. I used VBA macro before and thought of it again to save some of my time.
 Things is changing very fast, the new javascript based custom fuction is the mainstream. The initial one I followed the tutorial, however I didn’t find any way to add it into &amp;#34;My Addin&amp;#34; as described in microsoft doc site. I don’t have administrator rights on my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate a customized rule of spectral using chatgpt</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2023/08/generate-a-customized-rule-of-spectral-using-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2023/08/generate-a-customized-rule-of-spectral-using-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>Background I didn’t find a rule implementation of spectral at stoplightio and github to lint the rule that resources should be nouns in REST API. stoplight mentions that Use Nouns for Resource Names, however there is no another article about that. I was bothered by that for a while to the point I want to give it a try to implement my rule for that.
 There are several existing implementations about this rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>run redux-saga examples</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/07/run-redux-saga-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2020/07/run-redux-saga-examples/</guid>
      <description>run redux-saga examples TL;DR:
 yarn yarn build
 I run into module not found issues when I try to run those examples under the repository of redus-saga. Even following comments in github issues and stackoverflow, those solutions don’t work out.
 Scripts in the package.json of the root folder don’t work for examples.
 After run yarn &amp;amp;&amp;amp; yarn build, can change directories to those examples and run them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
