<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>azure on My learning and diary</title>
    <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in azure on My learning and diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 12:01:10 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackliusr.github.io/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Export resources and reconstruct resources in azure</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/01/export-resources-and-reconstruct-resources-in-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 12:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2024/01/export-resources-and-reconstruct-resources-in-azure/</guid>
      <description>My credit of Visual Studio Professional Subscription azure is $50. In the past two days, I activated my subscription. I didn’t go IaC way to setup my POC environment as I did’t have enough time to do that. After I setup more services, the 10 credit is used. It can be quickly used up if resources are kept running. I know there is a way to import existing resources as I used terraform in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change appsettings.json without restart in app service</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2023/10/change-appsettings.json-without-restart-in-app-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 20:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2023/10/change-appsettings.json-without-restart-in-app-service/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, zero downtime is normal, you can’t believe that in azure app service changes in &amp;#34;app settings&amp;#34;, App Service triggers an app restart. The alternative ways to do avoid that is to use sentinel key with App Configuration. however App Configuration will cost a little. Do we really need to use App Configuration to achieve that ?
 The naive and obvious way is that changing appsettings.json files via entering the app services using kudo console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Microsoft azure or google cloud</title>
      <link>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/10/learning-microsoft-azure-or-google-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackliusr.github.io/posts/2022/10/learning-microsoft-azure-or-google-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Today when I leant SRE course from cloudskillsboost, the first course is google cloud foundation. SRE is great. cloudskillsboost should be best place to learn SRE as it is originated there.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
